欢迎回到这个关于ASP.NET Core. 的视频系列。
hey welcome back to this video series about ASP.NET Core.
我的名字是jeff writs
my name is jeff writs
我是jon galloway
and I'm jon galloway
john 你知道吗
and john. you know what
我们都是美国人
we're both americans
而且，
and,
尽管他试图成为加拿大人
although he tried to be a canadian and
我想早点成为加拿大人
I try to be a canadian earlier
失败了，
failed,
但是我的英语说得不好
But I barely speak English well
我学习另一种语言
and I learn another language
我知道很多人都知道
and I know a lot of the folks out there
我相信，你不把英语作为第一语言
I'm sure you don't speak English as your first language
怎么做？
how do ?
我该如何本地化并确保我们的ASP.NET核心web应用程序能够更好地为那些不是美国人，不说英语的人工作。
how do I go about localizing and making sure that our ASP.NET core web applications  work better  for those folks who  aren't american and aren't English.
你知道这是一个很好的问题我已经做了一段时间的ASP.NET演示了
You know that's a great question and it's one that   I've been doing ASP.NET presentations for a while
这是我多年来对以前的ASP.NET版本所做的，我从来没有一个好的答案。
and it's one that I've got over the years for previous versions of  ASP.NET and I never had a good answer.
人们会说
and people would say like
你好，你在德国。
hello, you're in germany.
你跟我说的是关于ASP.NET的我的网站在德语中是行不通的，你知道
you're speaking to me about to me about ASP.NET and my sites don't work in German.  you know
我要对它说抱歉。
I'm going to say yeah sorry about that.
幸运的是，在ASP.NET core中我们有一个很好的解决方案，他们已经考虑过这个问题，我对全球化和本地化的支持程度感到非常满意
Fortunately with ASP.NET core we've got a good solution for that they've for that they've actually thought through this and I'm really pretty happy with  the level of support for globalization and localization
在全球化文档中
Here in the docs the globalization
在ASP.NET核心文档中，本地化有很多信息。
localization in ASP.NET Core doc is  there's a lot of information here.
我喜欢的另一件事是看贡献者的名字。
another thing that I love is just looking at the name of contributors.
例如，nadeam和hisham都不是来自美国的是本地化专家
for instance nadeam and hisham both folks that are not from the us and are   experts in localization
并为这个贡献了代码和文档
and have contributed  code and documentation to this
因此，看到全球社区为我们的全球化本地化工作做出贡献是令人兴奋的
so it's exciting to see the global community contributing to our globalization localization efforts
棒极了！
Awesome！
第一期全球化和本地化定义
first term as far as globalization and localization definitions
所以全球化是让我的应用能够说多种语言的过程，
so globalization is the process of making my application  able to speak many languages,
好的
ok
本地化是实际上说的步骤
localization is the step of actually saying
很好
great
现在让我们把它作为一种特定的文化或语言，
now let's target it for a specific culture or language,
对，
right,
好的
ok
所以全球化集中到一个受支持的本地化把语言列表中。
So globalization is opening it up and then localization is focusing it to a list of supported languages alright.
好吧
all right
对的
right
所以这里有很多不同的东西
so there's a lot of different things in here
这里有关于如何使我的内容本地化的信息。
there's information about how to make my content localizable.
你将看到的主要内容是你的代码和Razor
the main things that you're going to see is your code behind and your razor
这是两个主要地方
right those are your two kind of main places
我们来快速浏览一下，
so we'll take a quick look at this,
这就像我说的，这是一个很长的文档，本地化你的应用程序有一些复杂性。
this is like I said this is a long document and there are some complexities to localizing your applications.
所以我建议你去找文档来深入研究这个问题。
and so I refer you to the docs to really dig into this.
但就目前而言，我们必须考虑这个问题。
But for the time we have to look at this.
我先给你们看一下。
I'm going to show you first of all.
这是一个本地化示例
here is a localization sample
这是在文档中准备的
this is prepared this is actually in that docs
它通过这个Demo来演示
it goes through and it talk to you through this exact demo here ok.
好的
okay
所以
so
在这里设置了一些东西，
with some things that are set up here,
首先是我的服务。
first of all in my services.
我现在运行这个应用程序，
so I'm running the app now,
我有一个更小的屏幕
so I've got a smaller screen available
但在我的服务中，我们实际上是配置服务的一部分，
but  in my services we actually as part of configuring services，
建立在这一点上的能力是说这里是我支持的本地化的，对吧。
built into that is the ability to say things like here are my Supported Cultures， right.
所以我可以通过，我可以说，
so I can go through and I can say,
下面是我的应用程序所支持的本地化
here are the supported cultures that my application has
这是我全球化后的内容这是我本地化的语言
so this is the  after I've  globalized it this is these are the languages I've localized for
好的
ok
所以我可以通过设置两个SupportedCultures 我也可以进入并说设置一个DefaultRequestCulture
so I can go through and set both SupportedCultures and I can also go in and say  set a DefaultRequestCulture
因此，如果浏览器不呈现本地化的语言，
So if the browser does not present a culture that doesn't say the local languages,
这是我可以在这里写的，我可以指定它，甚至所有这些东西，因为它们在代码中。
then this  is  I can go through here and I can  specify that and I could even  for all these things because they're in code.
我可以运行我自己的自定义逻辑，甚至可以访问它的数据库。
I can go through and run my own custom logic may be even hit it database.
好的
okay
这就是这一部分。
so that's that part there.
让我们来看看这个应用，
let's take a look at this this app actually,
你会在页脚看到的例子应用程序的语言是英语。
so this is you know this is an example application you'll see down in the footer. it says language is english.
如果我下拉
if I drop this down.
现在我是法国人
now I'm in french right
所以这部分是本地化的
and so portions of this have been localized  this is using the  resources
好的，请大家看一看
OK  take a look in a second
但这表明了他来自哪里
but this is showing kind of where this comes from.
我的法语不太好，但是我们可以
I my french is not so good so I'm you know but we can
我们可以在这个网站上四处看看，我们可以看到这里的一些东西。
we can look around through out the site and we see we can see them some things in here.
举个例子，让我们看看我们是否有一个联系页面
so for instance let's see if we've got a contact page
是的，我们的联系页面是本地化的
and yes our contact pages  is localized right
所以我们可以看看这些资源是如何建立起来的
so so we can actually take a look at how these resources are set up
当另一件事
when one other thing
实际上，在我们讲这个之前我想指出一点有趣的事情
actually before we jump into that I want to point out just a small funny thing
我想展示一下
I wanted to show this off
并且
and
在这里，他们已经在这个小的下拉菜单中使用了英语和法语。
here they've built in this little dropdown for english and french.
这是在示例中建立的
that's built into the sample
同样的，这并不是在ASP.NET核心中构建的，这不是一个标准的特性
into the same ，That's not built into ASP.NET Core,that's not a standard feature
所以我没有意识到那是真的。
And so I didn't realize that was there.
幸运的是，我将向你们展示一些你们可以使用的东西。
fortunately for you I'm going to show you something that you can use.
这是一个例子，这个扩展我可以进入并改变我的语言，我的文化
so this is an example， this is an extension where I can go in and change  my  language， my culture
当我把它发送回浏览器时，我可以在这里
as I'm sending it back to the browser ，so I can actually in here
如果我把它设置为法语，你可以在测试应用程序时使用它。
if I set this to french and you can use this as you're testing your applications.
这是个本地化开关
this is a culture switcher
对的
right
所以你也可以在你的应用中做这个
and so you can go through and do that in your apps as well
本地化转换器所做的事情就是让浏览器发送法语内容
So that will what that culture switcher does is it effectively changes the browser to send that header that says accept the french language information
对，没错。
exactly, yeah.
现在让我们看看这些资源是如何配置的。
so now let's look at how those resources are configured.
这些实际上是标准的默认方式。NET本地化是使用资源文件。
so these are actually the standard kind of default way that  .NET localization is using resource files.
如果我进入其中一个
so if I go into one of these
这些实际上是.resx文件或XML
these are actually .resx files or XML
但是这里有一个编辑器
but there is an editor thing for this
我可以为visual studio编辑插件，它内置在菜单UI中
that I can editor plugin for visual studio， it's built in to the menu UI
是的，是的
right, yeah
这是一种标准的做法
so that's kind of the standard way to do this
这是一个可扩展的系统，可以提供其他的方式
it is an extensible system where I can kind of， I can supply those other ways
但这是一种内置的工具
but this is kind of with the tooling as is built into this
然后看我如何在一个视图中点亮这个。
and then when I look at how I light this up in  a view for instance.
我们使用这个本地化器。
we use this Localizer.
这个本地化的简洁之处就在于它
what's neat about this localized is it
它实际上是关键，是我的默认语言
it actually is the key，  is  my default culture.
那么，我想说的是
so what ? what I can say here is
如果没有指定的内容或者是我的本地文化，我将使用主页
if there's nothing specified or if it's my local culture.  I'm going to use homepage
否则我就把它放进来。
otherwise I'm going to pull it in.
我将用它来查找它应该是什么。
I'm going to use that is the key to look up what it should be.
动态感觉
dynamic sense
如果你在过去使用过本地化
if you've used localization in the past
尝试深入并理解，这是令人沮丧的，
it can be frustrating to try and dig through and and am  understand,
如果你在过去使用过本地化
if you've used localization in the past
尝试深入并理解，这是令人沮丧的，
it can be frustrating to try and dig through and and am  understand,
你知道很难读懂本地化的页面
you know it's hard to read localized  pages
因为本地化的页面本身可以是这样的。
because the localized pages themselves can be  that  they can be.
它们可以是一串钥匙
they can be it's a bunch of keys
这是一堆你知道的奇怪的难读的东西。
it's a bunch of you know strange hard read things.
举个例子，如果我们看这里如果我们看一下我的联系页面，
so for instance if we look at this now here if we look at my contact page,
你会发现这些本地化的字符串会让你的手机本地化，比如本地化支持。
you'll see that these localized strings say things like localize your phone， look  Localizer support.
所以这是很容易读懂的
So it's actually pretty readable right
对吧？
right？
如果我想看一下，在我的联系页面上支持的本地化字符串是什么。
and then if I want to look at  well what is the localized string for for instance support on my contact page.
现在我进入联系人
Now I go into contact
我可以看到这里的支持
and I can see here support
你知道这就是它从那个方向下拉出来的。
and you know that's what it's pulling in from that one right.
对。
right.
所以它实际上只是显示了那个字符串
so it actually just showing that string there
但它解释了它的来源。
but it's explaining that's where it came from.
现在我看到了一个层次结构，它看起来就像是这些资源文件的命名约定。
Now I'm seeing a hierarchy and it looks like like a naming convention for these resource files.
是啊，没错。
yeah Yeah! that's true.
这就是视图被拉进来的方式，
so that's that's how they're being pulled in based on you know exactly here's the views
它实际上映射了views->home
and it actually maps views->home
然后在下面得到了相同的Views ->Home，对。
and then down here we've got the same this is Views -> Home. Right.
如果我在我的home视图中
so if I'm  in my home view
我的主索引视图页面。
my home index view page.
是的
yeah
我指的是本地化的
and I'm referencing the localized
我已经指定了主页项
and I've specified the home page  item
我指的是本地化的
and I'm referencing the localized
我已经指定了主页项
and I've specified the home page  item
在索引中。
in the index are there.
它会进入视图主页索引资源并寻找相同的主页项
it's going to reach into the views  home  index resource  and look for  that same home page  item
哦，这是在半路上
oh there it is about halfway down
好的。
okay yeah.
这就是index.fr
and so there we are  this is the Index.fr
如果我有其他的，如果我有日本的索引。jaa.resx会更好。
and then if I had others if I had you know japanese index.jaa.resx  It's better.
对的
right
你说的是
and you were making the point that
它使用我的默认语言作为这些键的索引器
it uses my default language as the indexer for these for these keys over here
这样的话，如果我不是一个说英语的人写这个
that way  if I'm not an english speaker and am writing this
也许我是法国人，我在写，我想提供德语翻译之类的东西。
and perhaps I'm french and I'm writing it and I want to provide german translations and whatnot.
我可以使用我的母语，作为访问这些语言的关键
I can use my native language, as the keys  to  access these
完全正确！
exactly！ Fanatstic！
这样一来，你的视图就可以被你的本地语言所读取
and so then your view can be readable by you know  whatever your local language  is in that case
完全正确。
exactly.
这真的很方便。
so that's really handy.
所以这是主要的事情当然我们也看到了
so that's kind of the main thing there's also of course we're also seeing
像这样，这也是我的控制器。
things like, here is my  for the controller as well.
对的
right
这里我有我的主页控制器的资源
so here I've got resources for my home controller
让我们看一下我的控制器
and let's take a look in my controllers
在上面，
up here,
我们来看看我的主控制器。
and we'll look at my home controller.
我们已经通过了这个IStringLocalizer。
and so we've passed in this IStringLocalizer.
对吧？
right ?
然后我们就可以进行注入了，它只是在这里查看数据信息，通常我只是设置一个字符串而不是使用本地化器
and then we're able to its injected and it's just  view data  message here normally I would just set a string instead I use localizer
调用这个服务，我已经注入了这个键。
and calling to that service I've injected and then again  that key.
所以我的控制器代码仍然可以读取我的默认语言
so my controller the code is still readable by me and my default language
我的当地语言，对吗？
might my local language ，right
然后它会在运行时本地化
and then it's actually just going to localizer this at runtime
再一次是本地化的或者知道它在主控制器类内部操作
so once again the localized or knows that its operating inside of the home controller class
没错，我们会找到主控制器资源
exactly. we are going to find the home controller resource
请说
yep
注射
to inject from
我明白了，
i got it,
好的，是的
ok ，yeah
这就是它的全部内容。
so that's that's really all there is to it.
另一个很酷的东西我想给你们看的是resx文件，是微软本地化的东西
One other cool thing I want to show you is resx files ，are kind of a Microsoft localization thing
它对一些人来说很有用，工具就在那里，所有这些
and it works great for some people ，the tooling is all there and all that
我已经和一些做了很多本地化的人谈过，Po文件是微软之外的一种标准
I've talked to some people that do a good amount of localization and Po files are kind of standard outside of the microsoft Dev world
好的
ok
PO文件格式非常简单
PO files the format is pretty simple
它也可以很容易地传递给本地化者，他们可以做他们知道的工作
and it can also be easy to pass off to a localizer, they can do the work they know their
PO文件很容易处理，然后他们可以把它传递给你，所以我必须把这些PO文件转换成resx！
PO files it's easy to work with and then they can kind of pass it back to you.   So do I have to convert those PO files to resx!
这是很酷的一件事
now, so that's a cool thing
orchard project or Orchard Core，如果我在这里查找，我们去orchardproject.net，我相信，
So the orchard project or Orchard Core, so if I lookup here. Let's go to orchardproject.net I believe,
Orchard NET 提供的CMS，
so Orchard is a .NET powered CMS ok,
好的
ok
而orchard core支持PO文件本地化。
and orchard core has support for PO file localization.
好的
ok
而orchard core支持PO文件本地化。
and orchard core has support for PO file localization.
这是在文档中
so this is actually in the docs
如果我们去看docs.microsoft.com 的全球化，本地化部分中寻找。
here if we go to you know the  the docs.microsoft.com looking in the looking in the globalization, localization section.
他们谈论的是PO文件，并建议使用orchard core
they talk about PO files and recommend using s  are orchard core for that.
这里你看到的是一个示例
so here you're seeing here is a sample profile.
它可以更简单，重量更轻，
it can be a lot simpler and lighter weight to use,
使用po文件而不是resx文件你知道它有很多xml文件
use a po file as opposed to resx file which  you know has a lot of xml to it
这就是它的标准，
So that's kind of the standard for it,
至于它的外观，然后你会看到应用程序内部，这里我们要做的是Services.AddPortableObjectLocalization
for how it looks and then here you'll see inside the application,  so here we're doing Services.AddPortableObjectLocalization
这就是点亮的东西
so that's really that lights that up
否则我们就会像之前那样，配置默认的和受支持的本地化，
otherwise we'd just configure those default and supported cultures just like we did before,
对的
right
这是最后一件事我想给你们展示的是我的PO文件。
so that's and then the final thing I want to show you here is my PO file.
对的
right
这是最后一件事我想给你们展示的是我的PO文件。
so that's and then the final thing I want to show you here is my PO file.
好的
ok
好了，你们知道，我们讨论了全球化的问题
Okay, so you know to kind of circle way back, we talked about what globalization
在国际化的过程中，全球化使你的应用程序本地化
In the process of internationalizing an applicatio globalizing is making your application ready to be localized
本地化是你真正深入的地方，你说我支持以下四种语言
Localization is where you actually drill down ，and you say I support the following four languages
你们知道我是如何打开ie的，这是我写这些字符串的方式，
and you know here's how I turn on the ie here's how I write those strings,
我们研究了如何使用定位器，无论是在视图还是在我的代码中
We looked at how you can use the localizer， both in views and in my code
最后我们看了一下从哪里可以得到这些字符串
and then finally we looked at where I can get those strings from
我们可以从resx文件中提取它们
and we can pull them either from a resx file
这在visual studio工具中得到了支持，它是一个xml文件。
and that's supported in the  in the visual studio tooling and it's an xml file.
如果你喜欢使用po文件，我们用orchard core支持集，我们展示了一个使用它们的例子，
if you prefer to use po files we looked at how orchard core support set and we showed a sample of using them,
太棒了
that's terrific
最后我也会回到这里
so I'll circle back finally too
如果你想深入研究这个问题
if you want to dig deeper into this I
强烈推荐这些文档和示例，这些人是全球本地化和ASP.NETCore的专家
highly recommend the docs on this and the sample file again these people are worldwide experts on localization and ASP.NET  Core
他们在ASP.NET Core之前就已经做过了，这些人是你想要学习的人
and they've been doing it before ASP.NET Core with the thing. These are the people you want to learn from
极好的
terrific
这就是我们对全球化和本地化和ASPNET Core的看法。
so that's it that's our look at globalization and localization and  ASPNET Core.
感谢您的加入，我们希望您能在我们的视频中看到更多的视频。
thank you for joining us and we hope you watch some more of our videos on aspinet core.
待会儿见。
catch you later.